The holy terror is back!
Sister Act 2: Back in the Habit is a music, comedy film directed by Bill Duke.
Deloris Van Cartier is again asked to don the nun's habit to help a
run-down Catholic school, presided over by Mother Superior.
And if trying to reach out to a class full of uninterested students wasn't bad enough, the sisters
discover that the school is due to be closed by the unscrupulous chief of a local authority.
Deloris Van Cartier, played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Sister Mary Patrick, played by Kathy Najimy.
Rita Louise Watson, played by Lauryn Hill.
Florence Watson, played by Sheryl Lee Ralph.
Mother Superior, played by Maggie Smith.
Father Maurice, played by Barnard Hughes.
Sister Act 2: Back in the Habit is a 1993 American jukebox musical comedy
film, directed by Bill Duke, and released by Touchstone Pictures.
A sequel to the 1992 film Sister Act, it is loosely based on the life of
Crenshaw High School choir instructor Iris Stevenson.
The film follows Whoopi Goldberg reprising her role as Deloris Van Cartier, who
returns to assist her nun friends in saving their struggling school.
Maggie Smith, Kathy Najimy, Wendy Makkena, and Mary Wickes
reprise their roles from the original film.
While Sister Act 2 was a modest box office success, it was
initially panned by critics compared to its predecessor.
However, the film gained a devoted following over time, particularly for
its energetic musical performances and uplifting themes.
It starred Lauryn Hill in her breakout role, alongside Sheryl Lee
Ralph, Alanna Ubach, and Jennifer Love Hewitt.
Notable members of the film's choir include R&B singer Ryan Toby of
City High and The War and Treaty singer Tanya Trotter.
Gospel singer Erica Campbell of Mary Mary also appeared in
the film as a member of the opposing choir.
The film explores themes of nun, education, music
competition, sequel, singing nun.
The tone is lighthearted.